[Music]
Welcome to this Business Central launch
edition of 2025 release wave 2. This
session is about manufacturing
analytics.
Why would we invest in this area? Well,
using both reports and business
intelligence can really help you get a
better understanding of your performance
and waste in your production processes.
And in this wave, we are completing our
modernization of this area both with
existing reports and with the PowerBI
app. The updated PowerBI app for
manufacturing
makes it much easier to spot production
issues, reduce waste and keep operations
running smoothly. Um and similarly with
the modernized reports, uh these
insights can help your production teams
or your manufacturing teams um just get
the data you need without customizing
anything and just save some time and
helping uh your team make smarter
decisions.
So I mentioned modernization. This is
actually a theme uh completing that this
this is a theme for for this particular
wave. Um and for manufacturing we have
completely modernized our reporting and
BI or analytics story period. What does
that mean? That means we are finishing
we have finished the PowerBI app and we
have modernized all uh analytical
reports either giving them Excel layouts
and maybe also word layouts.
So for the updated PowerBI app,
the main um improvements we have here is
simply we have addressed feedback. We
try to take the app through the normal
business scenarios and then we spotted
small things that just should be better.
And uh one of the bigger things that I
just want to show you here is that every
measures every number you see in the app
now show data in a universal unit of
measure for capacity that you choose
inside business central. Just one
example of that here. I'm showing it for
the current utilization report but this
goes across every single measure uh
related to capacity is you notice that
on the the right here in on the actual
report you see uh something called show
capacity in days and that matches both
the caption but also the numbers uh what
you have chosen to set up in your
manufacturing setup in Business Central
um as show capac capacity. So, so those
now completely match in in the BI part
of your ERP
for our built-in reports. This means
this section is not for PowerBI. Uh you
should definitely go and update or
install the PowerBI app for
manufacturing and just try out the new
features. We'll also document of course
all of those in uh in do in the re node
and in Microsoft learn. But uh for
built-in reports, what does modernize
mean? Well, it means that we wanted to
enable end users to analyze data in
Excel and also change the layout, which
is why we have chosen Excel and Word as
the layout options for manufacturing and
analytics reports.
And then the second part of the
modernization is what we call
discoverability.
So that uh we also added inclient help
and uh added articles in Microsoft learn
our documentation so that customers can
actually find the reports and learn what
they can use them for.
This is just one of the examples a
recent example um this is the where used
top level manufacturing reports and what
you see here is the legacy layout uh for
that report. it just gives you a PDF and
there's no kind of navigation sorting
filtering ability here with the the new
version here of so we kept the report we
just added a second layout which is an
Excel layout and uh with this first of
all it has all the capabilities of Excel
so you can filter sort um it also has a
printable um worksheet
um in the in the workbook so if you
really want to print. You can also do it
there. But another thing is that you can
take this layout and make it your own
and then upload that uh just using Excel
for discoverability. Here is an example
of the inclient help. So what you see up
um when you open the request page, each
of the reports now have what we call a
teaching tip. um you don't have
necessarily to have then enabled
everywhere but when you choose um the
caption here you get some notification
of or idea of what this report is about
if you choose show help or open the help
pane. Uh that same message is shown here
including a link to the uh documentation
article for this particular report. And
if you then choose that, here's just an
example of of this how it looks in
Microsoft Learn. Each of the reports
have a section of what the report shows
as well as a section on how you use the
report and then uh some tried links.
These articles might also have
alternatives alternative ways to analyze
this particular scenario. could be that
this report that have been in the
product for 30 years now also have a
counterpart in PowerBI if that's the
case will also have a section on
alternative ways to do that analysis
now um we were actually supposed
wave 1 um I had a video there on
manufacturing reports as well where I
mentioned these I I think 8 six updated
and two completely new reports. They
were supposed to ship in 26.2
uh for some reasons I don't have to talk
about here. We needed to postpone that
until version 27.0. So if you're
watching this video for version 27 or
2025 release wave 2, all of these
reports are there as well as three more.
So on the bottom here you can see
quantity explosion of uh bill of
material where I use top level the one I
showed you and a completely new report
for produ production order list. So all
the reports that we postponed plus three
new is what you get here in version
27.0.
If you want to learn more about
manufacturing analytics as a whole, we
have an aka link for that that takes you
to this landing page for manufacturing
analytics. So, aka.ms/bc
manufacturing analytics. So, go check
that out. We should have everything
covered with personas, use cases,
everything you need to know if you need
to analyze data for your production uh
should be here from this landing page.
And that's it. Just a few things. If you
have not been here before, um the the
product group uh here we have a LinkedIn
page that we definitely want you to to
follow. This is where you get all the
news uh weekly news um deep dives uh you
you just get like um you get the news
way before uh the launch event. So
definitely go and and follow us on
LinkedIn. And uh we also uh since you're
watching this on YouTube, uh we have a
YouTube channel uh not only for the
launch events or the the launch
editions, but also everything else from
tips and tricks and deep dives and under
the hood podcast and and what have you.
So the aka.ms/bc
YouTube uh is definitely a place where
you should get your learning on if
you're interested in Business Central.
And a few more resources and then I'll
uh stop. BC all aka.ms/bcall
is a partner landing page for all the
the aka links relevant for you. If you
have anything as a partner, any
discussion or question, um the our
Yammer site is the place to go. No
customers are there. So if you're a
customer, sorry, that's not for you.
aka.ms/bc
yammer, go there to um to learn more.
And for both customers and partners, we
have office hours roughly once a month.
And uh that link here, BC office hours,
is where you get to learn more about all
of that. So with that, thank you so much
for watching. Um have a great other um
videos um or or learning resources for
for our 2025 release wave 2. Thank you.